Christopher Ashby

Global Security Leader | Board Member | Strategic Transformation Executive

(518) 577-8597

ashbyc@mac.com

https://ashbyca.com

PGP: 3679D138AE307F2A

Summary

Highly experienced pragmatic executive, trusted advisory, and strategic problem solver taking a collaborative approach on resolving complex security problems that enable businesses to achieve their outcomes successfully across all levels of the organization.

Demonstrated success architecting, improving, and managing global cyber security related programs with a consistent willingness to align and respond to the evolving threat landscape, business outcomes, and regulatory requirements. Confident in leading diverse teams dedicated to assessing business risk, defining appropriate mitigation, managing enterprise execution, and enhancing operational efficiency.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Global Head of Cybersecurity Architecture and Operations

Fresenius Medical Care, Waltham, MA, 2022—Present Collaborate across leadership teams with direct accountability to build and oversee the cybersecurity strategy, vision, and roadmaps with a relentless focus on balancing security with simplification.

- Responsible for the development and execution in delivering next generation cyber security capabilities across the enterprise.
- Active role model, mentor, and actively promote a culture of engineering excellence to strengthen the technical expertise and know-how of our cyber architecture teams.

Senior Security Engineer, Global Security Solutions

Alexion Pharmaceuticals, New Haven, CT, 2019–Present

Created and led the incident response, threat hunting, purple team, and cyber hygiene programs across the organization. Acted as a threat reduction subject matter expert in various working groups to continuously drive down risk and increase resiliency across the organization. Other key responsibilities included:

- Collaboratively worked across the IT enterprise to resolve identified issues including configuration weaknesses and other software weaknesses.
- Worked closely with executives on mitigation strategies to ensure the appropriate levels of risk were maintained.
- Implemented continuous process improvements in cybersecurity incident response tactics, techniques, procedures.
- Served as a role model, teacher, mentor for security analysts, and IT workforce who weren't well versed in cyber risk or security operations.

SKILLS

Enterprise Security Architecture

Adversarial Emulation

Policy and Governance

Project Management

Cloud Computing

Creative Thinking

Cyber Threat Intelligence

Security Orchestration and Automation

Employee Training and Development

Data Privacy

Executive Engagement

Cyber Risk Management

Posture Management

Education

Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA

Executive Education 2022-2022 Chief Information Security Officer (CISO) Certificate

Harvard, Cambridge MA

Graduate Certificate 2020-2020 Cyber Risk Management in the Information Age

Ithaca College, Ithaca NY

Graduate Certificate 2020-2020 Cyber Security Leadership

Cyber Intel Watch Commander

Digitalware, New York, NY, 2019-2019

Responsibilities included developing the long-term strategy and executing day to day management of a 24x7 Fusion Center environment which included a multifaceted elite team of technology engineers, data scientists, security analysts, and threat researchers serving multiple clients across various verticals including banking, entertainment and, local state governments.

- Conducted daily strategic threat briefings for high profile customers that included in-depth threat-actor assessments, TTPs, and risk reduction remediations.
- Executive level interactions in supporting city agencies C-suite particularly CISO, CSO, CIO, and CTO.

Director, Information Security

CBS Corporation, New York, NY, 2013–2018

Developed and managed a global threat intelligence strategy that provided visibility around providing a holistic view of the security landscape across the enterprise.

- Managed and automated the collection of OSINT & Commercial threat feeds producing operational intelligence for remote teams.
- Generated and delivered routine business readiness intelligence providing an early warning of potential threats
- Created and distributed threat metrics, advisories, and daily threat briefings that clearly articulated the security landscape to executives.

Principle IT Security Analyst

GLOBALFOUNDRIES, Malta, NY, 2011-2013

Work as a team lead responsible for US security operations within a semiconductor manufacturing facility. General responsibilities included security operations, architecture, and security solutions design as necessary to support a mission critical global operation.

- Provided technical leadership to the enterprise for the information security programs and team members.
- Maintained, managed, and frequently engaged with third-party relationships.
- Recommended, implemented, and maintained, new and existing security infrastructure including network IPS devices, Firewalls, Proxies, and VPN appliances.
- Continuously assessed threats, risks, and vulnerabilities from emerging security events using various organic and vendor implemented solutions.

Information Security Specialist

The Active Network, Saratoga, NY, 2010-2011

Worked as a cyber security subject matter expert providing support and leadership on various company initiatives including:

- PCI compliance testing for Level1 Merchant Accreditation
- Network Security architecture reviews and audits
- Vulnerability discovery and Penetration testing

Certifications

Certified Risk Information Systems
Control - CRISC

Certified Information Systems Security Professional - CISSP

Certified Cloud Security Professional - CCSP

Certified Information Security Manager - CISM

Publications

PenTest Regular Magazine Pass-The-Hash Attacks Published April 2013

Article explaining the post exploitation attack techniques used to elevate privileges and/or create new authenticated sessions.

PenTest Extra Magazine
Automating Malware Analysis
with Cuckoo
Published: August 2013

Article on implementing an automated technique to aid in the identification and analysis of suspicious software.

PenTest Regular Magazine Extending Cuckoo Framework Published: November 2013

Article describing some of the advanced features, capabilities, and extensibility of the Cuckoo Platform.

Professional Associations

Ithaca College Board Member

InfraGard Southern CT Member

Operations Security Trust Member

ISC – Southern CT Chapter Member